A Guide to the Malcolm Wilson Papers FA075
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Speeches - Coller, Arthur Memorial Lecture Series, October 16, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 110)
- Speeches - Constitutional Convention Statement, October 27, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 111)
- Speeches - Elizabeth Seton Academy Dedication and Graduation, May 22, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 112)
- Speeches - Elizabeth Seton College Dedication, September 30, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 113)
- Speeches - Empire Boys' State, June 28, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 114)
- Speeches - Empire Girls' State, June 26, 1962, June 28, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 115)
- Speeches - Empire State Chamber of Commerce, February 1, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 116)
- Speeches - Fordham College Alumni Association, February 2, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 117)
- Speeches - Fordham Prep School Commencement, June 18, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 118)
- Speeches - Fordham Prep School Alumni, February 23, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 119)
- Speeches - Fordham University Alumni, January 24, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 120)
- Speeches - Fordham University - Lowenstein Center Dedication, May 15, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 121)
- Speeches - Fordham University School of Law Dedication, November 18, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 122)
- Speeches - Franciscan Brothers Centennial, May 5, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 123)
- Speeches - Friendly Sons of Mercy, March 16, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 124)
- Speeches - Friendly Sons of St. Patrick (New York City), March 17, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 125)
- Speeches - Gibbons, Bishop High School Commencement, June 24, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 126)
- Speeches - Good Counsel College Commencement, May 31, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 127)
- Speeches - Governor's Committee on Minority Groups in News Media, June 18, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 128)
- Speeches - Governor's Conference on Volunteers, December 6, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 129)
- Speeches - Halsted School Commencement, June 13, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 130)
- Speeches - Hein, Sidney: Eulogy, April 4, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 131)
- Speeches - Hillcrest Jewish Center (dummy file) (Box 5, Folder 132)
  Related Archival Materials note
  See also Coller Memorial Lecture, Folder 110
- Speeches - Iona College Buildings Dedication, April 22, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 133)
- Speeches - Iona Prep Commencement, June 8, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 134)
- Speeches - Jewish Teachers Association, March 19, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 135)
- Speeches - Ladycliff College Commencement, May 29, 1961, May 26, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 136)
- Speeches - Lexington School for the Deaf Commencement, June 19, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 137)
- Speeches - Lutheran Church Missouri Synod, July 8, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 138)
- Speeches - Manhattan College Commencement, June 9, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 139)
- Speeches - Marymount College Commencement, May 29, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 140)
- Speeches - Marymount Secondary School Commencement, June 1, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 141)
- Speeches - Masonic Breakfast, New York City, April 10, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 142)
- Speeches - Mercy College Commencement, June 2, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 143)
- Speeches - Mercy College Groundbreaking, December 12, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 144)
- Speeches - Molloy Catholic College for Women Commencement, July 2, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 145)
- Speeches - Monroe County Fair Interfaith Ceremonies, August 17, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 146)
- Speeches - Mt. St. Mary on the Hudson Commencement, June 1, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 147)
- Speeches - Mt. St. Vincent College Commencement, June 2, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 148)
- Speeches - Mt. St. Vincent College Commencement, June 5, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 149)
- Speeches - Nassau County Village Officials Association, October 8, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 150)
- Speeches - National Conference of Christians and Jews (photos), December 10, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 151)
- Speeches - Nazareth College Commencement, June 3, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 152)
- Speeches - New Rochelle College Commencement, June 6, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 153)
- Speeches - New York City Police Department Holy Name Society Breakfast, April 3, 1960, April 8, 1973, April 5, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 154)
- Speeches - New York Press Association, September 20, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 155)
- Speeches - New York State Bar Association, January 26, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 156)
- Speeches - New York State Bar Association, Municipal Law Section, January 29, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 157)
- Speeches - New York State Police Chiefs Association, July 27, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 158)
- Speeches - New York State Society of Newspaper Editors, June 20, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 159)
- Speeches - New York State Theatre Opening, Lincoln Center, April 23, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 160)
- Speeches - Niagara University Commencement, June 1, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 161)
- Speeches - Norwegian Constitution Day, May 15, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 162)
- Speeches - Notre Dame College of Staten Island Commencement, June 3, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 163)
- Speeches - Notre Dame Convent School Commencement, June 2, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 164)
- Speeches - Our Lady of Victory High School (dummy file), December 12, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 165)
  See also Mercy College Groundbreaking, Folder 144
- Speeches - Pace College Commencement, June 15, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 166)
- Speeches - Polish Constitution Day, May 1, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 167)
- Speeches - Primary and Secondary Education Resolution, June 28, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 168)
  Resolution introduced by Malcolm Wilson at National Conference of Lieutenant Governors, Eighth Annual Meeting, Denver, Colorado. Commented on by Malcolm Wilson at meeting of Associated Industries (September 19, 1969), copy of resolution: consider desirability of compressing 12 year span of primary and secondary education into a shorter period.
- Speeches - Revenue Sharing Press Release, July 21, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 169)
  Malcolm Wilson urges Annual Meeting of Lieutenant Governors to redress imbalance between federal government on one hand and local governments on the other.
- Speeches - Robb, Eugene: Eulogy, August 21, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 170)
  Robb was publisher of "Capital Newspapers" in Albany.
- Speeches - Rosary Hill College Dedication Ceremony, September 20, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 171)
- Speeches - St. Bonaventure University Commencement, June 5, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 172)
- Speeches - St. Don Bosco Chapel Anniversary (Elmira), May 6, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 173)
- Speeches - St. Francis College Charter Awards Dinner, May 8, 1963, May 7, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 174)
- Speeches - St. John Fisher College Commencement, May 29, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 175)
- Speeches - St. Patrick's Day Parade (New York City) Sash Ceremony, March 6, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 176)
- Speeches - St. Pius X Preparatory Seminary Commencements, June 10, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 177)
- Speeches - St. Rose College Commencement, June 6, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 178)
- Speeches - St. Thomas Aquinas College Commencement, June 7, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 179)
- Speeches - St. Vincent's Hospital Addition Dedication, October 15, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 180)
- Speeches - St. Vincent's School of Nursing Commencement, May 30, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 181)
- Speeches - Second Panel Sheriff's Jury, January 24, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 182)
- Speeches - Siena College Commencement, June 3, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 183)
- Speeches - Smith, Gov. Alfred E., Memorial Foundation Dinner, October 17, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 184)
- Speeches - Stepinac High School Commencement, June 10, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 185)
- Speeches - Stony Brook Campus State University of New York Dedication, April 16, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 186)
- Speeches - Teachers Institute of Archidiocese of New York, February 5, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 187)
- Speeches - Ukrainian American Youth Association Center Dedication, September 20, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 188)
- Speeches - Urban Development Corporation Conference (Press Release), June 30, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 189)
- Speeches - Ursuline School Commencement, June 4, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 190)
- Speeches - USO Dinner, December 11, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 191)
- Speeches - Valhalla High School Commencement, June 27, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 192)
- Speeches - Vatican Pavilion Dedication at World's Fair, April 19, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 193)
- Speeches - White House Conference on Aging (Albany), June 16, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 194)
- Speeches - Youth Court Act Repeal (Statement by Malcolm Wilson), March 29, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 195)
- Speeches - Lieutenant Governor's Conference (Press Release), August 14, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 196)
- Malcolm Wilson Articles (Box 6, Folder 197)
  1) "Monitor" (Associated Industries), July 1961 2) "Monitor," November 1961 3) "Industrial Bulletin" (New York Department of Labor), July 1962
- Radio and Television Appearances (Box 6, Folder 198)
  1) Reorganization of Government, March 29, 1960 2) Barry Gray Radio Show, November 8, 1962 3) Page One (Off-Track Betting), November 17, 1963 4) Ed Bates Show, February 19, 1964
- Alphabetical Files, 1959-1973 (Box 6, Folder 199)
  Personal memos arranged alphabetically by person requesting Malcolm Wilson's assistance; political matters; "scandals."
- Photo Album; First Inauguration, January 1, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 200)
- Personal Photo Album, 1938-1973 (Box 7, Folder 201)
- Plans for Development of South Mall, 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 202)
- Temporary State Commission on the Capital City, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 203)
  Malcolm Wilson letter April 6, 1961 to Attorney General Lefkowitz requesting opinion on constitutionality of Commission; "Opinion" June 7, 1961 of Attorney General finding Commission constitutional.
- Capital City Commission, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 204)
  Press release from August 9 on retaining consultants.
- Capital City Commission, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 205)
  Press release from March 26 on land appropriation.
- Capital City Commission, 1961-1968 (Box 8, Folder 206)
  Press releases and budget numbers, September 1, 1961-September 19, 1968.
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, March 8, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 207)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, May 8, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 208)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, July 7, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 209)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, September 13, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 210)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, November 17, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 211)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, January 9, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 212)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, March 14, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 213)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, May 15, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 214)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, July 10, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 215)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, September 10, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 216)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, November 15, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 217)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, March 13, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 218)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, May 12, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 219)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, July 15, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 220)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, September 15, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 221)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, November 14, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 222)
- Coordinating Committee on the South Mall Project Progress Reports, January 15, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 223)
- World's Fair - New York World's Fair, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 224)
  Wilson correspondence with Robert Moses on disposition of Fair buildings.
- World's Fair - New York World's Fair, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 225)
  Brochure: Post Fair Expansion: Hall of Science.
- World's Fair - New York World's Fair, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 226)
  Brochure: plan for Queens Zoological and Botanical Gardens.
- World's Fair - New York World's Fair, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 227)
  Report on New York State Department of Public Works plan: proposed disposition of New York State Exhibition buildings.
- World's Fair - Malcolm Wilson's World's Fair Correspondence, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 228)
  Letters to and from J. Burch McMorran, New York State Superintendent of Public Works; copy of letter from Robert Moses to William F. Sloan, New York City Budget Director; memos; Wilson letters to Moses, S. Neil Corbin (counsel to NAR), John V. Thornton of Whitman, Ransom & Coulson (attorneys for World's Fair Corporation), Martin B. McKneally (counsel to New York State Commission on the World's Fair Corporation); Post-Fair Engineering report; miscellaneous correspondence on post-Fair plans; copies of contract between New York State and New York City to transfer New York State Pavilion to New York City.
- World's Fair - Malcolm Wilson's World's Fair Correspondence, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 0228A)
  Restricted material
- World's Fair - Malcolm Wilson's Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 8, Folder 229)
  Memos to Martin McKneally (counsel to World's Fair Commission) on transfer of title to New York State Pavilion; correspondence with Budget Dept.; memo on history and architectural value of New York State Pavilion (to counter demolition of Pavilion); Wilson memo to NAR (February 14, 196) on retention of Pavilion; original "Agreement of Participation between New York World's Fair 1964-1964 Corporation and The New York State Commission on The World's Fair;" letters on transfer to New York City.
- World's Fair - Brochure: Transfer (Return) of Flushing Meadows-Corona Park, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 230)
  Transfer to New York City; press clippings.
- World's Fair - World's Fair Photographs, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 231)
- World's Fair - World's Fair Photographs, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 232)
- World's Fair - Photographs, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 233)
  National Conference of Christians and Jews -- Wilson, Samuel Hausman, and Louis J. Lefkowitz.
- World's Fair - Legislature Bills Creating World's Fair, 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 234)
  Legislative Document No. 27 (1962) Report of Commission.
- World's Fair - Lincoln Center Agreement, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 235)
  People of the State of New York and Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts on the construction of the New York State Theatre.
- World's Fair - "Complete Design" of Buildings at World's Fair by Philip Johnson Associates, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 236)
- World's Fair - Malcolm Wilson Correspondence on World's Fair, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 237)
- World's Fair - Budget Department Certificates, 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 238)
  Approval of availability of funds.
- World's Fair - New York State Commission on World's Fair, 1962-1964 (Box 9, Folder 239)
  Minutes of meetings.
- World's Fair - Lease: Sterling Forest Management, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 240)
  Exhibit at New York State Pavilion.
- World's Fair - Contract: General Drafting Co., Inc., 1963 (Box 9, Folder 241)
  Map Pamphlet and Holder.
- World's Fair - Contract: Discovery Productions, Inc., 1964 (Box 9, Folder 242)
  Production of film to illustrate functions and operations of New York State Legislature.
- World's Fair - New York State Theatre Building, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 243)
  Copy of deed to City of New York; drafts of transfer agreement.
- World's Fair - Agreements, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 244)
  1) New York State Pavilion Food and Frank Shattuck on "62 Counties Restaurant." 2) People of the State of New York to City of New York; transfer of New York State Pavilion.
- World's Fair - New York State Pavilion, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 245)
  Deed to City and release by City to State: transfer of title.
- World's Fair - New York State Commission on World's Fair, 1963-1969 (Box 9, Folder 246)
  Audit Reports, 1963, 1964, 1966; statements on finances, 1966-1969.
- World's Fair - Contract for Construction, Heating of New York State Exhibit Buildings, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 247)
- World's Fair - World's Fair Brochures, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 248)
- World's Fair - Malcolm Wilson World's Fair Correspondence, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 249)
- World's Fair - Malcolm Wilson World's Fair Correspondence, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 250)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, December 1963-March 1964 (Box 9, Folder 251)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, April 1964 (Box 9, Folder 252)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, May 1964 (Box 9, Folder 253)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, June 1964 (Box 9, Folder 254)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, July 1964 (Box 9, Folder 255)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, August 1964 (Box 9, Folder 256)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, September 1964 (Box 9, Folder 257)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings, October, December 1964 (Box 9, Folder 258)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings: Special Events, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 259)
- World's Fair - Press Clippings: Tour "(County Name) Day", 1964 (Box 9, Folder 260)
- World's Fair - General Press Coverage, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 261)
- World's Fair - General Press Coverage, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 262)
- World's Fair - General Press Coverage, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 263)
- World's Fair - Malcolm Wilson Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1965-1972 (Box 9, Folder 264)
  Draft of speech, "The Commission's Work."
- National Conferences of Lieutenant Governors, 1967-1973 (Box 9, Folder 265)
- Governors' Club Dinners and Salute to Vice President, 1976-1976 (Box 9, Folder 266)
- Booklet: The Governors of the States, 1900-1974 (Box 9, Folder 267)
- Daily Diaries, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 268)
- Daily Diaries, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 269)
- Daily Diaries, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 270)
- Daily Diaries, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 271)
- Daily Diaries, 1963 (Box 10, Folder 272)
- Daily Diaries, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 273)
- Daily Diaries, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 274)
- Daily Diaries, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 275)
- Daily Diaries, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 276)
- Daily Diaries, 1968 (Box 10, Folder 277)
- Daily Diaries, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 278)
- Daily Diaries, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 279)
- Daily Diaries, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 280)
- Daily Diaries, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 281)
- Daily Diaries, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 282)
- Daily Diaries, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 283)